Guide to the Sloss Music Collection M0126
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sloss music collection
1811-1947
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sloss, Hattie Hecht
M0126
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Scope and Content
Autograph letters of musicians, singers, composers and conductors. Also postcards, autographs, and a few photographs, in English and German. Songbooks in Aleut, German, English, and possibly Danish,. 1821-1947.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Hattie Hecht Sloss with other materials donated by Siemon William Muller, Professor Alma Lowrey Williams, Watson Nicholson, and others.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Related Materials
Signed photographs from the Sloss collection are in the General Photograph Collection: Portraits (https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4083653)
Music; Songbooks.; Sloss, Hattie Hecht; Sloss, Hattie Hecht
- BACHANS, WILHELM (Box 1, Folder 1)
- BARTALINI (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - to Mr. Sears, undated; A.L.S.
- BEETHOVEN, LUDWIG V. 1770-1827 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Copy of letter to Rockel, undated
- BORI, LUCREZIA 1888- (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with covers., 6 April 1933 and 20 March 1934; 2 T.L.S.
- BRICO, ANTONIA (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in German and English with concert program and cover., 5 Jan. [1931]; A.L.S.
- DAMROSCH, FRANK HEINO 1859-1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, 16 May 1917.; T.L.S.
- DAMROSCH, WALTER JOHANNES 1862- (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, 28 Nov. 1901.; A.L.S.
  - to R.L. Wilbur, 12 Nov. 1934.; T.L.S.
- DOBROWEN, ISSAY (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in English with cover., 3 Jan. 1931; A.N.S.
  - A.P.C.S. to Mrs. Sloss, in German., 9 July 1931
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in German with cover., 3 Nov. [1931]; A.N.S.
- DOBROWEN, M. (see also: Issay A.P.C.S.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in German with cover., 28 Jan. 1931; A.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in German, with line and signature of Issay., 24 March 1931; T.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in German with cover., 4 Oct. 1931; A.L.S.
- ELMAN, MISCHA 1891- (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Autograph to Margaret Sloss, 4 March 1914.
  - Autographed photo to Mrs. Sloss, 15 Feb. 1913.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, 5 May 1914.; A.L.S.
- FLEISHER, LEON (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, 16 May 1943.; A.L.S.
- FLOOD, WILLIAM HENRY GRATTON 1859 - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - to Watson Nicholson, 28 June and 10 Aug. 1922.; 2 A.L.S.
- FOOTE, ARTURO 1853-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, 23 Dec.?; A.L.S.
- GERMAN, SIR EDWARD 1862-1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - unsigned letter quoting newspapers' praise of The Seasons., undated
- HARTY, SIR HAMILTON 1880-1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 15 Aug. 1931; A.L.S.
- HEERMANN, HUGO (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - to unknown, date?; 1 A.N.S. and 1 A.L.S.
- HERTZ, ALFRED 1872-1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover. to unknown, 23 Oct. 1923 n.d.; A.N.S.
- HEUSCHEL, ED (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - to Mr. Hecht, 1 June 1896.; A.L.S.
  - to Miss Hecht, with note signed [G.H.] with cover., n.d.; A.L.S.
- HEUSCHEL, LILLIAN B. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - to Hattie [Hecht], undated; A.L.S.
- IVES, CHARLES E. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - to Prof. A.L. Williams, 1933; A.L.S.
    Scope and Contents note
    Content: genealogy, esp. relationship between Prof. Williams and Ives (Source: Prof. Alma Lowry Williams)
- [LIEDERSAMMLUNG; 20 musik gesetzt.] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - songbook, in German, various composers, hand-copied, undated
- MARIO, QUEENA (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 10 Sept. 1930; A.L.S.
- MELBA, NELLIE (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 4 Feb. 1916; A.L.S.
- MELCHIOR, LAURITZ 1890 - (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., n.d.; A.L.S.
- MEYERBEER, GIACOMO (or JAKOB LIEBMANN BEER) 1791 - 1864 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - to unknown, with autograph of Alexander H. Rice attached to verso., 9 Aug. [1861]; A.L.S.
- MILHAUD, M. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 21 April 1947; A.L.S.
- MOZART FACSIMILES, two items. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- MOZART, CONSTANZE [transferred] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - to J. Spontini, Mar. 19, 1838.; A.L.S.
    Custodial History
    PLEASE NOTE: Item was transferred to the Memorial Library of Music (https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/9645653) with shelf number MLM 765.
- ORSINI, L. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - To Mons. Golterman, in French., 27 Sept. 1871; A.L.S.
- PADEREWSKI, JAN IGNACY (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - facsimile signature and handwritten line from menuet in A major. ( L.A.), Mar. 1900
- REMENYI, EDWARD (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - to unknown, 23 Dec. 1878.; A.L.S.
- RETHBERG, ELIZABETH 1894 - (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 5 March 1929; T.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 29 Aug. 1929; T.L.S.
  - A.P.C.S. to Mrs. Sloss, with cover in German., 24 Sept. 1929; (signed photo)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 17 March 1931; A.N.S.
  - A.P.C.S. to Mrs. Sloss, 17 Feb.; (photo)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 10 [Aug.] 1935; A.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover in German., undated; A.N.S.
- SEMBRICH, MARCELLA STENGEL 1858 - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in German., 23 March 1901; A.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover, in German., 11 Nov. 1901; A.L.S.
  - Autograph calling card, Nov. 1901.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover, in German., 3 Dec. 1901; A.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover, in German., 11 May 1904; A.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 11 May 1933; T.L.S.
  - T.N.S. to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 30 March 1933
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover, in German., undated; A.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., undated; A.N.S.
- SMITH, S.F. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Autographed hymn of America, 1894.
- SPONTINI, GASPARE 1774-1851 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - to [?], April 8, 1811.; A.L.S.
- STOKOWSKI, OLGA SAMAROFF (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, undated; A.L.S.
- STRAUSS, MME. JOHANN, calling card with note in [German?] (Box 1, Folder 37)
- TETRAZZINI, LUISA 1874-1940 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, in French., 20 Jan. 1911; A.L.S.
- TIBBETT, LAWRENCE M. 1896 - (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - T.L. (carbon) to L.T. from Mrs. Sloss, 31 Aug. 1933.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, 9 Sept. 1933.; T.L.S.
  - T.L. (carbon) from Mrs. Sloss, 22 Nov. 1933.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, 18 Dec. 1933.; T.L.S.
- TOVEY, DONALD FRANCIS 1875 - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - to James Speyer, July 31, 1901.; A.L.S.
- WALTER, BRUNO 1876- (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 4 Sept. 1946; A.L.S.
  - to Mrs. Sloss, with cover., 21 April 1947; A.L.S.
- Unidentified signed photograph (Box 1, Folder 42)
  (See Memorial Lib of Music #24)
- ALEUT (or ESKIMO) LANGUAGE SONGBOOK or HYMNBOOK (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Some printed pages, mostly holograph, author unknown, undated
- SANGE [DANISH?], 2 ms. songbooks with hand drawn and painted covers. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- GESANGE fur CLAVIER ODER PIANOFORTE GESAMELT von CONCORDIA ROHLER (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Ms. musical scores and lyrics in German, bound.
- SONGBOOK IN ENGLISH (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ms., bound, owner and possible copyist: Mr. Hamilton. Gift of Dr. Siemon William Muller.
- SUNDAY SCHOOL SONGBOOK ([John] Law) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ms., bound, Muller gift., 1821.
- A. HASWELL SONGBOOK (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ms., bound, Muller gift., 1826
- JOHN LAW SONGBOOK (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ms., bound, Muller gift., 1842.
- SONGBOOK (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ms., bound, hymns and psalms.
- NANCY KELLOGG'S SONGBOOK (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ms., bound, 1825
    Wm. Cullen Bryant piece in back.